i-payout.com 2017-07-31

# i-payout

Information Collection: i-payout is the sole owner of the information collected. i-payout collects information from our users at several points on our Website.

In order to use this Website and its service offering, i-payout will provide a Sign Up form for the user to register. During registration i-payout will ask for the following information:

First Name  
Last Name  
Street Address  
City  
ZIP or Postal Code  
Country  
Email Address  
User Name  
User Password  
Phone Number  
Government ID number (e.g. SSN or passport number)  
Security question  
Answer to Security question 

Question:  What does a non-U.S. user need to provide in place of the SSN that a U.S. user is required to provide?

Answer:  Positive ID using a permanent, government issued ID number, such as a passport number, National ID card, etc. Driver’s licenses cannot be used as they are not permanent and numbers on them can change at renewal or re-issue.

Due to governmental oversight of all financial transactions, the above-listed information is required to be collected by i-payout in order to offer our services to our users. This information is used to determine true identity and the authenticity of transactions conducted by our users. The need for the requested identification information and subsequent verification checks are mandatory as dictated by U.S. law. 

i-payout takes data security seriously and offers our users a secure alternative payment solution that can be used with confidence over the Internet as well as over all cellular phone networks. i-payout’s mission is to provide consumers with the most secure, reliable, fast and easy payment solution available for use on the Internet and cell phones. Users protect their accounts from misuse by selecting a unique Username (i.e., their Associate, Member or Distributor number or a self-chosen Username) and by selecting their own User Password during the sign-up process. Thereafter, users can quickly and easily access their funds and perform multiple transactions from their accounts. Passwords can easily be changed by the User and we highly encourage that users do so on a regular basis. 

Our Website has various features that automatically collect information from users to deliver requested content specific to each users' interests and to honor their preferences and requests. This information assists us in creating a Website that will constantly evolve to better serve the needs of our users. 

We store information that we collect through the registration form to create a profile of our users. A profile is stored information that we keep on individual users which details their viewing and transaction preferences. Consequently, collected information is tied to users' personally identifiable information to provide customized offers and improve the content and functionality of the site for users. 

A "cookie" is a small data file transferred by a Website to your computer's hard drive. i-payout is committed to continually improving the Web experience for our visitors. Currently, cookies are the most effective way of identifying unique, anonymous visitors and to document their navigation during visits. Cookies are typically classified as either "session" cookies or "permanent" cookies. 

"Session" cookies do not stay on your computer after you leave our Website or close your browser. The aggregate information collected permits us to analyze traffic patterns on our site. This can enable us over time to provide a better experience on our site by improving content or personalization and making our site easier to use. 

"Permanent" cookies are those that remain on your computer. They are used to facilitate shopping, personalization and registration services. For example, cookies can keep track of what you have selected to purchase as you continue to shop and allow you to enter your password only once on Web pages where a login is required. "Permanent" cookies can be manually removed by the user. 

Most browsers automatically accept cookies by default, but you can usually refuse cookies or selectively accept certain cookies by adjusting the preferences in your browser. If you turn off cookies, there may be some features of our Website that will not be available to you and some Web pages may not display properly. You can find information on popular browsers and how to adjust your cookie preferences at the following websites: 

Log Files

For internal purposes, we gather date, time, browser type, navigation history and IP addresses of all visitors to our Website. This information does not contain anything that can identify users individually. We use this information for our internal security audit log, trend analysis, system administration, and to gather broad, aggregate demographic information about our user base. We may combine demographic information supplied by users at registration with site usage data to provide general profiles, in aggregate non-personally identifiable form, about our users and their preferences relating to Website content and site advertising. We may share this composite information with our advertisers and business affiliates to help them better understand our services. 

Service Announcements

On rare occasions it is necessary to send out service related announcements. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, users may receive an email stating this. These communications are not promotional in nature. 

Customer Service

We have to communicate with users on a regular basis to provide requested services. Also, in regard to issues relating to their accounts, we reply via email or phone in accordance with users' wishes. From time-to-time, it may be necessary for our customer support team to contact an individual if there is a problem or issue with their account. 

Legal Disclaimer

Although we make every effort to preserve our user’s privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on us or our Website, or in a situation where a customer's behavior raises concern about the legitimacy of his or her account. 

Service Providers

In order for i-payout to provide its core service offering (secure, fast payments), it is required to share personally identifiable information with our other service providers that provide various services for us to complete our tasks. These can include electronic funds movement and processing companies, card transaction processing companies, banks and similar service providers. All our service providers maintain similar or even stricter confidentiality and data security features as i-payout. 

Business Transitions

In the event i-payout goes through a business transition, such as a merger, being acquired by another company, or selling a portion of its assets, individual user’s personal information will in most instances be part of the assets transferred. Users will be notified via email and via a prominent notice on our Website prior to a change of ownership or control of their personal information. If as a result of the business transition, our users' personally identifiable information will be used in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection of that information, then users will be given choice consistent with our notification of changes section. 

Links

You should be aware that other Internet sites that you link to from the i-payout site may contain privacy provisions that differ from the provisions of our Privacy Statement. To ensure your privacy is protected, we recommend that you review the privacy statements of other Internet sites you visit. 

Correcting/Updating/Deleting/Deactivating Personal Information

If users wish to change their personally identifiable information (such as zip code, phone numbers or their postal address), they can do so by going to their "Profile" page and making the appropriate changes. 

Notification of Changes

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this Privacy Statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances (if any), we may disclose it. We will only use information in accordance with the Privacy Policy under which the information was collected. 

However, if we are going to use a users' personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection, we will notify users via email. Users will then have a choice as to whether or not we may use their information in this different manner In addition, if we make any material changes in our privacy practices that do not affect the users information already stored in our database, we will post a prominent notice on our Website notifying users of the change. In some cases where we post a notice, we will also email users who have opted to receive communications from us by email, notifying them of the changes in our privacy practices. 

Contact Information

Please contact us with any questions or comments regarding this privacy policy at privacy@i-payout.com
